<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Kimberley&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Kimberley&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading Data from World Bank and US Government Websites</title>
      <link>/2017/05/05/downloading-data-from-world-bank-and-us-government-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/05/downloading-data-from-world-bank-and-us-government-websites/</guid>
      <description>To explore the relationship between economic factors and birth rate, locate and download economic indicator and birth rate data.
Project OverviewDataData on gross domestic product and birth rate for the world, the United States of America, and five groups of countries aggregated by income was located on the World Bank Data Bank website. Data for the period 1998-2015 was downloaded in comma-separated value (CSV) format. Information on birth rate by US State was obtained from the Centers for Disease Controlb</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing US Birth Rate from 1998 to 2015</title>
      <link>/2017/05/05/visualizing-us-birth-rate-from-1998-to-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/05/visualizing-us-birth-rate-from-1998-to-2015/</guid>
      <description>To explore the relationship between economic factors and birth rate, chart US birth rate over a time period with changing economic conditions.
Project OverviewDataPreviously gathered and tidied data on US births by State and year were read into a programming environment.
TechnologiesThe R programming language was used to read, transform, and plot data. Packages used included plyr, dplyr, data.table, and ggplot2, all from the tidyverse.
TechniquesData files in several formats were read into a programming environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Birth Rates and Economic Indicators from 1998 to 2015</title>
      <link>/2015/05/06/visualizing-birth-rates-and-economic-indicators-from-1998-to-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/06/visualizing-birth-rates-and-economic-indicators-from-1998-to-2015/</guid>
      <description>To explore the relationship between economic factors and birth rate, chart birth rate and economic indicators for several regions over a time period with changing economic conditions.
Project OverviewDataPreviously gathered data on birth rates and gross domestic product (GDP) per capita for the period 1998–2015 were tidied using a spreadsheet program and then read into a programming environment.
TechnologiesSome downloaded data were reformed into a tidy data file using Microsoft Excel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>