<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plot on Kimberley&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/plot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plot on Kimberley&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/plot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing US Birth Rate from 1998 to 2015</title>
      <link>/2017/05/05/visualizing-us-birth-rate-from-1998-to-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/05/visualizing-us-birth-rate-from-1998-to-2015/</guid>
      <description>To explore the relationship between economic factors and birth rate, chart US birth rate over a time period with changing economic conditions.
Project OverviewDataPreviously gathered and tidied data on US births by State and year were read into a programming environment.
TechnologiesThe R programming language was used to read, transform, and plot data. Packages used included plyr, dplyr, data.table, and ggplot2, all from the tidyverse.
TechniquesData files in several formats were read into a programming environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Birth Rates and Economic Indicators from 1998 to 2015</title>
      <link>/2015/05/06/visualizing-birth-rates-and-economic-indicators-from-1998-to-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/06/visualizing-birth-rates-and-economic-indicators-from-1998-to-2015/</guid>
      <description>To explore the relationship between economic factors and birth rate, chart birth rate and economic indicators for several regions over a time period with changing economic conditions.
Project OverviewDataPreviously gathered data on birth rates and gross domestic product (GDP) per capita for the period 1998–2015 were tidied using a spreadsheet program and then read into a programming environment.
TechnologiesSome downloaded data were reformed into a tidy data file using Microsoft Excel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>